你是个谨慎的人吗，米里奇先生？
You are a cautious man, Mr. Mirich?
谢谢你，扎维沙
Thank you, Zavisha.
我们可以这样称呼，不信任易腐烂的商品
Let's call it what it is: a distrust for perishable goods.
- 什么货物? - 人类
- What kind of goods? - Human race.
你不喜欢人？
You don't like people?
那女人呢？
How about women?
那就不一样了，我不知道我对人们的爱或恨
That's a different story. I don't know which is stronger,
哪种感觉更强烈，但我尊重他们
my love or my hate for them, but I certainly respect them.
历史上女强人比比皆是
History is full of strong women:
阿格丽皮娜，米丽特莎公主
Agrippina, Princess Militsa,
公爵夫人柳比莎，圣女贞德…
Duchess Ljubitsa, Joan of Arc...
第一个是被自己的儿子杀死的
First one was killed by her own son,
第二个被她女儿嫁给了杀害她丈夫的凶手
the second let her daughter marry the man who murdered her husband,
第三个…
and the third...
被绑在火刑柱上烧死了
she was burned at the stake.
你感到惊讶吗？
Are you surprised?
我必须承认我很惊讶，但这是一个令人愉快的惊喜
I must admit I am. But it's a pleasant surprise.
你不是第一个把我当成乡下村姑的人
You're not the first one to mistake me for a cowgirl.
- 很奇怪，不是吗? - 什么？
- Strange, isn't it? - What?
男人喜欢坚强的女人
That men love strong women,
但当他们找到了一个
but when they find one,
她用刀捅他们的时候，会哭得像婴儿一样
they cry like babies when she stabs them with a knife.
听着，我亲爱的尤瓦娜…
See, my dear Yovana...
我母亲是个很坚强的女人
my mother was a very strong woman.
- 是吗? - 是的
- Was she? - Yes.
她嫁给我父亲时才十六岁
She was sixteen when she married my father,
不久就有了我
and then she had me.
我最早的记忆就是他殴打母亲
My earliest memories are of him beating her.
打得很有规律，而且很残忍
He did it regularly and brutally.
有一天我父亲突然病了
One day my father fell ill,
他日渐衰弱，不久于世
he was withering, fading away.
大家都以为是因为他酗酒
Everyone thought it was because of his drinking,
但并不是，是我妈妈觉得她受够了
but no, my mother decided that she's had enough.
她慢慢地给他下毒，不是因为她小心谨慎
She was poisoning him slowly, but not because she was cautious,
不是的，而是因为她喜欢看他受苦
no, it was because she enjoyed watching him suffer.
他死的时候，我在浴室里发现了一瓶黄色的粉末
When he died, I found a bottle of yellowish powder in the bathroom.
我给了邻居的狗喂了一些
I gave some to the neighbour's dog...
到了晚上，它就死了
It was dead by the evening.
从那时起，我就决定了长大后要做什么
That is when I decided what I wanted to be when I grow up.
- 制毒师？ - 不是
- A poisoner? - No.
药剂师
A pharmacist.
这里面是不是撒了砒霜？
Is it sprinkled with arsenic?
如果你不尝尝，你就永远不会知道…
You'll never know if you don't try...
那你为什么不换换口味…
Why don't you, for a change...
尝尝我？
try me?
巴尔干半岛的阴影 第一季 第十集
BLACK SUN EPISODE 10
迪玛 · 塔纳西耶维奇
Dima Tanasiyevich
他一定是个好人
He must have been a good man.
你怎么知道？
How do you know?
好人很快就会被遗忘
Good people are quickly forgotten.
我在这里睡了很久了
I've been sleeping here for ages,
而你是第一个来看他的人
and you're the first one to come to his grave.
人们会来的
They'll be coming.
给你，为他的灵魂喝一杯
Here, get a drink. For his soul.
现在喝酒有点早
It's a bit too early for that.
迪玛 · 塔纳西耶维奇
Dima Tanasiyevich
愿你活一百年! 干杯！
May you live a hundred years! Here we go!
拜托，你不应该教他这些
Please, you shouldn't teach him that.
早上好，是那个小家伙吗？
Good morning. Is that the little guy?
是的
Yes.
普尔莎，给我们来杯咖啡，我们该走了
Prsho, give us a coffee. We should get going.
- 进展顺利吗？ - 当然
- Did that thing go well? - Of course.
任何问题在普尔莎这里都会顺利
It has to when you leave it up to Prsho.
闭嘴，普尔莎，去倒咖啡
Zip it, Prsho, and give us that coffee.
如果我不休息的话，就没有人照顾这个孩子了
I don't have anyone to look after the kid if I don't get a day off.
- 把孩子给普尔莎带吧 - 怎么？
- Give him to Prsho. - How?
让他带孩子去看看斯米利亚
Let him take the kid to Smilya.
- 她会高兴得跳起来的 - 你确定？
- She'd jump for joy. - Are you sure?
- 相信我 - 我不想麻烦你们
- Trust me. - I wouldn't want to intrude.
小孩怎么会是麻烦呢
How can a little child be an intrusion.
- 真的吗? - 来吧，没事的
- Really? - Come on, it'll be fine.
让你的咖啡见鬼去吧！你根本就没煮
The hell with your coffee! You can't even make it.
- 博雅纳，再见！ - 再见
- Boyana, see you later! - See you.
回家见，博雅娜
See you at home, Boyana.
听着，你必须…
Listen, but you have to...
不，米里奇先生，你不是在做梦
No, Mr. Mirich, you're not dreaming.
我们又认真起来了
Oh, we're on formal terms again.
你以为你可以摆脱我和我哥哥，是吗？
You thought you could get rid of me and my brother, didn't you?
我必须承认你是对的
I must admit you're right.
我从没信任过你
I never trusted you.
因为你不仅是一个塞尔维亚男人
Not only because you are a man and a Serb,
还因为你身上的某种东西
but because there's something about you.
某种…
Something...
不可抗拒的东西？
Something irresistible?
腐烂的东西
Something rotten.
在正常情况下，我不同意你说的，但是..
Under normal circumstances, I'd beg to differ, but...
当一个女人拿刀抵着他的喉咙时，怎么能反驳呢？
how can one say no to a woman holding a knife to his throat?
在我像宰猪一样宰了你之前，你得告诉我
Before I slaughter you like a pig you're going to tell me
基拉在多大程度上参与了这一切
to what extent is Kyro involved in all this.
他是否出卖了我们，我和我弟弟？
Did he sell us out, me and my brother?
你答应他什么好处了？
What did you promise him?
基拉老板是…
Master Kyro is...
什么事这么急？
What's so urgent?
你是来邀请我参加婚礼的？
You came to invite me to a wedding?
你差不多可以称之为婚礼
You could almost call it a wedding.
- 你是新郎? - 很接近了
- And you're the groom? - That's quite close.
但不是由牧师主持的婚礼，而是修道士
But instead of a priest, it'll be done by the Monk.
别跟我耍花样，我现在很烦
Don't fuck with me, I'm down in the dumps.
要是下地狱就好了
It'd be better if had gone to hell.
你这样已经有一段时间了
You've been acting like it for some time now.
你说什么？
What did you say?
你心烦意乱有段时间了，事情失控了
You're distracted and things are getting out of hand.
你是来审问我的吗？
Did you come here to question me?
你可以那样跟塔纳西耶维奇说话，但跟我不行！
You can talk to Tanasiyevich like that, but not to me!
- 我从来没有对你不尊重 - 好了，好了
- I was never impolite to you. - Okay, okay.
迪米特里耶维奇，我们是来告诉你，我们会破掉这个案子的
Dimitriyevich, we're here to tell you that we'll solve the case.
但请你不要妨碍我们
And to ask you not to get in our way.
你们要破这个案子？那无论你到哪都会遇到障碍
You're going to solve the case? Obstacles wherever you turn.
恐怕没有人能破这个案子
I'm afraid no one can solve this case.
我们会把贝尔格莱德犯罪组织的头目绳之以法
We'll get you the head of Belgrade organised crime...
前提是你要保证不放了他
That is, if you promise not to release him.
- 保证？你疯了吗？ - 别装傻了
- Promise to you? Are you insane? - Don't play dumb.
我想知道你有没有胆量让修道士受审？
I want to know whether you have the balls to put Monk on trial?!
否则，我会辞职，用其他方式解决问题！
Otherwise, I'll quit and resolve it some other way!
好吧，抓住那个修道士
All right, get the Monk.
如果有命令要释放他，就算是首相本人下的命令
If an order comes to set him free, be it from the Minister himself,
我也递交辞呈，同意吗？
I will hand in my resignation. Agreed?
首相不是我们最担心的
He's the least of our worries.
如果你接到日瓦科维奇将军的电话怎么办？
What if you get a call from General Zhivkovich?
即使我接到亚历山大国王的电话
Even if I get a call from King Alexander,
只要我还是警察局长
the head of Belgrade bandits won't be out of prison
贝尔格莱德的黑帮头目就不会出狱，抓住他
while I am the chief. Get him.
我会的
I will.
我们从未有过这样的对话
We never had this conversation.
如果你做了什么蠢事，我不会为你打掩护
If you do something stupid, I won't cover for you.
你的拉链没拉好
Your fly is undone.
基拉老板
Master Kyro,
你知道什么是忠诚吗？
do you know what loyalty is?
我想我知道
I think I do.
如果你想让某人对你忠诚
See, if you want someone to be loyal,
那么他们必须相信你
they have to believe in you.
一位希腊哲学家曾经说过
A Greek philosopher once said, "It is much better to be
成为人们信任的人，比成为他们爱的人更好
the one people trust than the one they love."
- 没错 - 是的
- True that. - Indeed.
我的人很信任我
My people trust me.
我才不管他们爱不爱我
I don't give a shit if they love me.
扎维沙，你爱我吗？
Zavisha, do you love me?
要诚实
Be honest.
- 不爱，老板 - 看到没？
- I don't, boss. - See?
- 那你你相信我吗？ - 绝对相信，老板
- Do you trust me? - Absolutely, boss.
- 你可以走了 - 谢谢
- You're free to go. - Thank you.
我会解释清楚的
I'll make myself clear.
尽管有些小误会，但我们还是商业伙伴
Despite minor misunderstandings, we are business partners
我们必须相互信任
and we have to trust each other.
所以你和你的人
Therefore, if you and your flock of sheep
如果你想安全离开这个城市，我希望你能帮我一个忙
wish to leave the town safely, I expect a favour from you.
我要你的革命者死
I want your revolutionary dead.
我可以指望你的忠诚吗，基拉老板？
Can I count on your loyalty, Master Kyro?
可以
Yes.
在楼下等我，我很快就过去
Wait for me downstairs, I won't be long.
我们可以一起吃早餐
We could have breakfast together.
我在葬礼上把达维多维奇小姐介绍给了加布里埃尔
I introduced Ms. Davidovich to Gabriel at the funeral.
所以她也会人头落地？
So her head will roll too?
不，这意味着…
No, it means....
我们不想再发生意料之外的事
we don't want something unexpected again.
他们会见面的
They will meet.
他将有机会知道她是谁
He'll have a chance to see who she is.
只有这样，我们才有谈判的筹码
Only then can we start negotiations with our cards on the table.
虽然现在看来，已经有人
Although it seems someone has already spoken candidly
和那位年轻的小姐坦白了
with the young lady.
你是在暗示是我吗？
Are you implying it was me?
阿瓦库莫维奇先生，看在上帝的份上，就像你们塞尔维亚人常说的
Mr. Avakumovich, for God's sake, as you Serbs like to say,
我相信雷亚奇先生没有恶意
I am sure Mr. Rayachki didn't mean anything bad.
我肯定…
I'm sure...
他没有恶意
he didn't mean anything bad.
好了，先生们…
All right, gentlemen...
就这样吧
That's how it's going to be.
- 我们打烊了 - 我知道
- We're closed. - I know.
我们要找费奥多·谢尔巴基长官
We need Captain Fyodor Sherbacky.
- 你知道他在哪儿吗？ - 谁知道？
- Do you know where he is? - Who knows?
好吧，听着
Okay, listen...
是你们需要我，而不是我需要你们
It is you who need me, not the other way around.
如果你现在不让我进去，我就会离开，你们再也找不到我
If you don't let me in now, I'll be gone Lord knows where.
等着
Wait.
- 又是你，督察 - 我们得单独谈谈，上尉
- It's you again, inspector. - We need to talk, captain. Alone.
让我们单独谈谈
Leave us.
你找到我要的东西了吗？
Did you find what you have promised me?
是的，你会拿到矛的
I did. You'll get the spear.
既然你已经等了这么久，为了表示歉意
And because you had to wait so long,
我会额外奉上你的好朋友——修道士
I'll throw in something extra, your friend, Monk.
我要做什么才能获得这份大礼呢？
To what do I owe such generosity?
我需要你和你的人协助逮捕他
I need you and your men to arrest him.
我的人不是宪兵，不做逮捕的工作
My men and I are not gendarmes. We do not apprehend people.
是我来逮捕他，不是你
I am going to arrest him, not you.
- 让我先看看矛 - 还不行
- Let me see the spear first. - Not yet.
一旦修道士进了监狱，而被你杀掉
Once Monk is behind the bars, not with your bullet in his head,
那时你就能拿到矛了
that's when you'll get the spear.
你又在跟我玩游戏
You're playing games with me again.
如果你信守承诺，而我毁约
If you keep your side of the bargain, and I screw you,
你可以杀了我
you can kill me instead of him.
但是如果你杀了那个修道士，就算你杀我一千次
But if you kill the Monk, you'll never see the spear,
你也不可能拿到矛了
even if you kill me a thousand times.
如果你毁约，我连他一起杀
If you lie to me, I'll kill him too.
没问题，我接受
I'm prepared to accept such an agreement.
好吧，这房间里竟然有两个傻瓜
Here we are: not one, but two fools.
你知道帝国是怎么建立的吗，米兰？
Do you know how empires are forged, Milan?
你当然不知道，你只是一个步兵
Of course you don't, you're just a foot soldier.
你的工作是攻击，射击，杀人，然后被杀
Your job is to assault, to shoot, to kill, and be killed.
亲爱的…
My dear...
帝国是一块块石头，一块块砖头
an empire is built stone by stone, brick by brick,
一具具尸体
corpse by corpse.
石头磊得越多
The longer you amass the stones,
尸体越多，帝国就越强大
the more corpses you pile up, the stronger your empire.
你明白吗，老朋友？
Do you understand, old friend?
我们不是朋友
We're not friends.
你说什么？
What did you say?
我们当然不是
Of course we're not.
我们是旅伴
We are travelling companions.
我在掌舵，你在划船
I'm at the helm of the ship, and you're rowing.
我必须承认我钦佩你的诚意
I must admit I admire your sincerity
以及你向前看的决心
and your resolve to move forward.
你把那个妓女的尸体处理掉了吗？
Have you disposed of that whore's body?
- 是的 - 好吧
- I have. - Fine.
剩下的就交给我们了
Now, we're going to take care of the rest.
- 下面得人都准备好了吗？ - 准备好了
- Are the people ready? - They are.
你呢？
And you?
我？
What about me?
你准备好了吗，米兰？
Are you ready, Milan?
我时刻准备着
I'm always ready.
该死！请冷静！
Dame! Dame, please calm down!
我们现在在他的地盘，他们人太多了
We're on their turf. There's too many of them.
- 你才冷静点，基拉！- 我们没机会了
- You calm down, Kyro! - We don't stand a chance.
那个混蛋割断了你妹妹的喉咙！
That bastard has slit your sister's throat!
- 那是... - 那是什么！
- It was... - What was it?!
一场意外
An accident.
基拉，你他妈的臭傻逼！
Kyro, you motherfucking Shylock!
如果我现在割了你的喉咙
If I shoot you here now like a dog,
那会是意外吗？
would that be an accident?
- 你他妈的! - 冷静点，戴姆！
- You motherfucker! - Calm down, Dame!
我不想冷静下来
I don't want to calm down.
等我看到那个狗娘养的药剂师
I'll be calm when I see that pharmacist son of a bitch
把他的肠子捏在手里！我就冷静了！
holding his intestines in his hands!
拿上你们的武器，准备战斗！
Get your weapons and get ready for war!
大开杀戒！
And for the slaughter!
哦，督察，该去修剪一下你的头发了
Oh, Mr. Inspector, time to get your hair trimmed.
我不会因为你不逮捕我的同志起诉你
I won't charge you because you don't arrest my comrades.
我要以你的大嘴巴逮捕你
I'll arrest you for your big mouth.
有顾客的消息吗？
Any news about the customer?
他在里面等着呢
He's inside, waiting.
请进，督察！
After you, inspector!
是我，你在看什么？
It's me. What are you staring at?
我不确定你会不会来
I wasn't sure you'd come.
别乱动
Don't move.
我不会的
I won't.
以防万一，我带来了，给你
I brought it. Just in case. Here you go.
我得把这玩意儿带到别的地方去
I have to take this shit somewhere.
等我搞定了，我一定会干掉那些混蛋
I'll get those bastards when I'm done.
你要知道，你的老朋友没有杀她
Just so you know, your old friend didn't kill her.
把责任推到你身上只是为了方便
It was just convenient to put the blame on you.
别担心，我会找到那个凶手的
Don't worry, I'll find the one who did.
他躲不过我的
He can't hide from me.
去找个安全的地方躲起来
Go find a safe place and lay low.
满腔怒火的人注定会犯错误
A man consumed with anger is bound to make a mistake.
我会干掉那些德国混蛋
I'll finish off those German fuckers.
我保证
I promise.
我希望你失败
Well, I hope you fail,
这样我就可以亲自把他们切成碎片
so I can cut them into pieces.
保重，我的战友
Take care, my brother-in-arms.
你也是，长官
You too, my captain.
总有一天，当我回来的时候，不会是今天这样子
One day, when I return, not like this,
而是骑着白马
but on a white horse,
你加入我党，我就让你当警察局长
you'll join the party and I'll make you the police minister.
我不在乎你的党派
I don't care about your party.
我也一点都不在乎局长
And I couldn't care less about the Ministry of Police.
优惠出口股份公司"Prizad"
Privileged Export Joint Stock Company "Prizad".
一旦你加入了"Prizad"就再也没有回头路了
Once you join the "Prizad" there's no coming back.
请在这儿签两个名
Two signatures here, please.
官僚主义正在杀死我们，米尔卡
Bureaucracy is killing us, Milkica.
别再抱怨了
Stop whining.
想想你所得到的，你应该感到高兴
You should be rejoicing considering what you have been given.
只要我看到你的签名，我就会很高兴的，部长
I'll be rejoicing, minister, as soon as I see your signature.
当然可以，米尔卡，你能在外面等一下吗？
Certainly. Milkica, could you wait outside, please?
当然
Of course.
参议院将在明后天开会
Senate will sit in a day or two.
将军和每个人都打过招呼了
General has had a word with everyone.
放松，农产品出口已经掌握在你和上帝的手中
Relax, agricultural exports are in yours and God's hands now.
我会把西红柿和黄瓜留给上帝
I'll leave tomatoes and cucumbers to God,
但是罂粟及其衍生物仍然属于我
but poppy and its derivatives remain in my domain.
- 干杯 - 干杯！
- Cheers! - Cheers!
然后呢？
And?
我有机会通过这次测试吗？
Do I stand a chance of passing this trial?
就我而言，见到你的瞬间就通过了
As far as I am concerned, you've passed at first sight.
你是否可以把自己
Are you allowed to perceive yourself separately
和组织分开？
from the organization?
我是一个有血有肉的人
I am a man of flesh and blood.
我注意到了
So I've noticed.
但你也可以抑制自己的欲望
But you are also a man who can curb his urges,
一个准备抑制自己，进而追求更高目标的人
a man prepared to suppress his inclinations to a higher end.
- 你在诱惑我吗？- 绝对不是
- Are you tempting me? - By no means.
我不做徒劳无功的事
I don't indulge in futile endeavours.
你认为他们是徒劳的？
You think they're futile?
如果不是，那两个老头就不会派你来引诱我了
If they weren't, the two old men wouldn't have sent you to tempt me.
你觉得我应该建立什么样的关系？
And what do you think I am supposed to establish?
首先，我的提议是可行的
First of all, is my offer is viable.
是吗？
Well, is it?
这取决于你认为我能提供什么
It depends on what you think I'm offering.
我的任务是警告你我们已经准备好了
My task is to warn you that we're ready,
以防这是个陷阱
in case this is a trap.
我注意到了
Duly noted.
关于生意上的事，你还有什么要告诉我的吗？
Do you have anything else for me as far as business is concerned?
有，你身边那个警察
Yes, that cop who's shadowing you.
- 你吃醋了？- 有点
- Are you jealous? - A little,
但那只是因为他对你的迷恋
but only because of his obsession with you.
我相信像你这样的女人
I am sure that a woman like you
绝不会屈服于这样一个人渣的魅力
would never succumb to the charms of such a ruffian.
而且，我们当然也不希望他出席我们的会议
And, we certainly wouldn't want him present at our meeting.
别担心，我会处理好的
Don't worry, leave him to me.
我要你信守诺言
I will hold you to your word.
我们现在能换个话题吗？
Can we change the subject now?
当然
Finally.
- 干杯 - 干杯
- Cheers. - Cheers.
- 晚安 - 晚安
- Goodnight. - Goodnight.
你自己说的，生意优先
You said it yourself, business first.
说到生意，有人告诉我
When it comes to business, I was told you mentioned
你提到过还有一个脑袋要落地
a head that needs to roll.
是的
Yes.
你想知道是谁的吗？
And you'd like to know whose?
我当然很想知道
I don't see what else I might be interested in?
别担心，到时候你就知道了
Don't worry, you'll find out just at the right moment.
把这当作是一种预付款吧
Consider this an advance.
现在我真的得走了
And now I really have to go.
我们走，督察！
Let's go, inspector!
基拉！
Kyro!
是我，基拉老板，别开枪！
It's me, Master Kyro, don't shoot!
我没有武器！
I'm unarmed, Master Kyro!
我是来帮你的！下车
I came to help you! Get out.
基拉老板，我想和你谈谈！
Master Kyro, I want to speak to you!
谈话的阶段已经结束了！
Our conversations are finished!
进来! 开门！
Get in! Open up!
盯着那两个人！
Keep an eye on those two!
先听我说完，然后再杀我！
Hear me out first, and then kill me!
- 说来听听 - 我老板是个叛徒
- Let's hear it. - My boss is a traitor,
他背叛了你和我，我会处理他的
he has betrayed you, and me. I'll take care of him.
让我先解决掉他，这样我们才能做生意
Let me get rid of him so we can do business.
你是个好人，我们不要互相残杀
You're a good man, Let's not kill each other.
我们应该做生意！
We should be doing business!
骗子! 他想骗你！
Lying son of a bitch! He's trying to trick you!
- 闭嘴！- 你闭嘴，你个傻逼！
- Shut up! - You shut up, you son of a bitch!
- 基拉！- 他们都是一样的！
- Kyro! - They are all the same!
这不会有好结果的
Kyro. This is not going to end well.
我知道不会的
I know it won't.
冲！
C'mon!
拿汽油来，我们要烧了这个地方
Bring the gasoline, we'll torch this place.
等等，给我五分钟，我会把他带出来
Wait! Give me five minutes, I'll bring him in.
给你五分钟
You have five minutes.
达米安
Damyan,
是我，塔尼！我要进来了！
it's me, Tane! I'm coming in!
如果他杀了我，你知道该怎么做
If he kills me, you know what to do.
我来了，达米安！
I'm coming Damyan!
你是来要债的吗
You came to settle your debt.
回家吧，达米安
Go home, Dane.
忘了贝尔格莱德吧
Forget about Belgrade,
忘了你那该死的革命
forget that fucking revolution of yours.
那我被杀的妹妹呢? 我也应该忘记她吗？
And my slayed sister? Shall I forget her as well?
我会跟杀害你妹妹的凶手算账
I'll settle the score with the man who killed your sister.
我向你保证
You have my word.
塔纳西耶维奇先生，你是言出必行的人！
Mr. Tanasiyevich, a man of his word!
这是我仅有的品质了
That's all I have left.
如果我们再见面
If we meet again,
我们还是朋友吗？
shall we meet as friends?
你永远是我的朋友
You, Dame, will always be my friend.
你也是我永远的朋友，长官
And you mine, captain.
你确定你能坚持到底吗？
Are you sure you're strong enough to go all the way?
是的
Yes.
你决不能忘记这个程序
You must never forget the procedure.
如果你遵守它，它将成为你的盟友
If you abide by it, it will be your ally.
如果你忽略它
If you disregard it,
它会反过来对付你
it will turn against you.
放心吧，塔基叔叔
Don't worry, Uncle Tacky.
干得好，米兰，干得好
Well done, Milan. Well done.
就像你说的，老板，我只是个士兵
As you said, boss, I'm just a foot soldier.
我必须得说，这是一个相当有效的方法
And quite an efficient one, I must say.
干得好，米兰
Well done, Milan.
基拉老板和那个革命者在哪里？
Where are Master Kyro and the revolutionary?
修道士
Monk...
我以为你很聪明，但你是个白痴
I thought you were smart, but you're an idiot.
怎么回事，米兰，你把我出卖给俄国人了？
What is it, Milan, you sold me out to the Russians, huh?
看看是谁在说话？！
Look who's talking?!
谁？！
你他妈的叛徒！
You fucking traitor!
去死吧！
Go to hell!
米里奇先生，我们又见面了，果然是在教堂
Mr. Mirich, we meet again, in a church of all places.
- 塔纳西耶维奇督察 - 把他铐起来
- Inspector Tanasiyevich. - Cuff him.
我知道你是个愚蠢的警察，但你不可能蠢到
I knew you were a stupid cop, but you can't be that stupid
以为我会让你把我铐起来
to think that I am going to let you cuff me.
左边还是右边？
Left or right?
裁缝，我们说好的
Tailor, we have an agreement.
走吧，亲爱的…
Off you go, my darling...
这么长时间你都在哪里？
Where have you been so long?
我们一直在找你，朋友
We've been looking for you, my friend
走吧，你这个懦夫！
Go, you wimp!
左边还是右边？
Choose. Left or right?
塔尼，你的徒弟想干什么？
Tane, what's this apprentice of yours want?
你没教好他
You didn't teach him well.
他应该找你退学费
He should return the tuition money.
左边还是右边？
Left or right?
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
现在我们已经完成了，是时候专注于主要的事情了
Now that we're done, it's time to focus on the main thing.
正式的入会仪式
The official initiation ceremony
要等到我们下一次大型聚会，但是…
will have to wait until our next big gathering, but...
我先荣幸地宣布
unofficially, I have an honour to announce
你已经被我们接受了
that you have been accepted into our order.
我不穿那个
I won't be needing that.
戴维维奇小姐，圣殿骑士团的首领
Miss Davidovich, Master of the Order position...
不是一家可以继承的银行
is not a bank that can be inherited.
- 不是吗？- 你必须自己争取
- Isn't it? - You must earn it.
此外，这个职位不能由女性担任
Besides, the position cannot be held by a woman.
那么给你们做面具的玛丽亚女士
And Ms. Maria, the one who makes your masks,
她是男的吗？
is she a male?
玛丽亚·奥尔西奇女士是我们教会的灵魂
Ms. Maria Orsich is the soul of our order,
因此是个例外
and therefore an exception.
无论如何，谢谢你带来你父亲的王冠
In any case, thank you for bringing your late father's regalia.
我们会把它放在圣殿里，作为遗物保存
We will place it in the temple and keep it as a relic.
我想这个足够
I guess this argument will be enough
让你再破一次例
for you to make another exception.
至于优点，阿瓦库莫维奇先生…
And as for the merits, Mr. Avakumovich...
你把这里的秩序带到了崩溃的边缘
you brought this order to the brink of collapse.
你差点让银行破产
You almost bankrupted the bank.
更不用说我差点就要把它卖了
Not to mention that I was this close to confiscating it.
你发起了一场大屠杀
Instead of getting this relic quietly,
而不是暗中悄悄的拿到这个圣物
you have caused a bloodbath,
然而你的事情败露只是时间的问题
and it was only a matter of time when you were going to be found.
在我看来不是所有被砍下的头颅都是有意义的
It seems to me that instead of all the heads that were severed,
只有一个人头必须落地
there was only one that had to roll.
你要去哪儿？
Where are you going?
我赶时间，伙计，我有约在先
I'm in a hurry, man. I've got commitments.
除非你给我你答应过的东西，否则你哪儿也不能去
You're not going anywhere until you give me what you've promised.
- 好吧 - 矛在哪儿？
- Fine. - Where's the spear?
给，拿着
Here. Take it.
你把圣物揣在口袋里？
You were carrying a relic in your pocket?
对你来说，它是一件神圣的东西，而对我来说
For you, it is a sacred object; for me, it's a piece of metal
它只是一块白痴们为之杀戮和死亡的金属
that fools are prepared to kill and die for.
再见，队长，谢谢你
Farewell, captain. Thank you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
雷阿奇基先生，从现在开始你要对此负责
Mr. Rayachki, from now on you are responsible for this.
马上把它送到维也纳去
Take it to Vienna right away.
对不起，这是我的职责
Excuse me, but that is my duty.
你的职责是呆在我身边
Your duty is to stay by my side.
我有一个特殊的任务给你
I have a special assignment for you.
不用我多说，你必须把它保护好
Needless to say, you must guard it
就像你的掌上明珠
as the apple of your eye.
迪米特里耶维奇，你至少可以给我一支烟
Dimitriyevich, you could have at least offered me a cigarette.
我以为俄国人给你的钱能让你买点好烟
I thought the Russian money could get you something better than this.
如果你想要的话，我可以给你一些法国烟或者美国烟，随便什么
I can send you some if you want, French or American, whatever.
我会安排两个犯人和你一起
I'll arrange for two inmates to join you.
你会像火车头一样喘粗气，只不过不是美国或法国的
You'll be puffing like a locomotive. Only not American or French...
而是塞尔维亚的
but Serbian.
塔尼
Tane.
你们的军官真粗鲁
Your officers are really vulgar.
他们到处逮捕守法公民
They go around arresting law-abiding citizens.
乡下的泥土还挂在他们的鞋子上…
The provincial mud still dripping from their shoes...
然而他们却想在这里玩法律与秩序
and they'd like to play the law and order here.
这样可不行
That won't work.
米里奇先生
Mr. Mirich...
- 你可以叫他修道士 - 闭嘴！
- You can call him Monk. - Cut it out!
- 米里奇先生... - 什么事？
- Mr. Mirich... - Yes?
我希望你知道我们有证据
I hope you're aware that we have proof
还有你罪行的见证人
and the witnesses of your misdeeds.
我必须承认我很震惊
I must admit I was shocked
得知这样一位受人尊敬的守法公民…
to learn that such a respected, honourable citizen...
一个名声显赫的商人竟然是…
a man of immaculate reputation is...
是什么？
Is what?
是贝尔格莱德犯罪团伙的头目
Is the head of Belgrade's main criminal gang.
是这头猪告诉你的吗？
Did this pig tell you that?
好吧，我的证词和他的不一样
Fine, it'll be my word against his,
我的律师会对抗你的检察官
my lawyers against your prosecutors,
我的证人会对你的证人不利
my witnesses against your witnesses.
对你来说，是我的名声对抗你的名声
And for you, it'll be my reputation against yours.
老实说，我不确定你能不能活着
And frankly, I'm not sure you'll wake up
当明天的警察局长了
as a chief of police tomorrow.
你在威胁我吗？
Are you threatening me?
我们这是变成私仇了吗？
Are we on personal terms?
拍政客马屁救不了你，相信我
Sucking up to the politicians won't save you, trust me.
怎么？你是不是有种了？
What? Did you just grow balls?
你呢？你他妈瞅啥瞅？
And you? What the fuck are you looking at?
你想看我的种吗？
You want to see my balls?
- 局长！- 塔尼，塔尼！
- Chief! - Tane, Tane!
- 我给你看，你这个混蛋... - 把他弄走！
- I'll show you, you fuck... - Get him off!
放开我！
Let me go!
- 冷静点 - 放开我！
- Calm down. - Let me go!
请冷静
Please, calm down.
出去
Get out.
那么，你不想让我和你一起去？
So, you don't want me to go with you?
不想
No.
我一直想告诉你…
I've been meaning to tell you...
你已经失去了眼中的火花
You've lost that spark in your eye.
你让我想起雾中的鹅
You remind me of a goose in the fog.
你的意思是…我像一只黑公鸡？（此处应该是指被玛雅迷惑）
You mean, like a blackcock?
是的，但我不想冒犯你
I do, but I didn't want to offend you.
你最好不要太信任她
You'd be better off trusting her just a little bit less.
像我这样的人…
Guys like me...
可以为爱而凋谢，但不会失去理智
They can wither for love, but not lose their head.
晚安
Goodnight.
恐怕这是违反规定的
I'm afraid this is against the rules.
什么规定？
What is?
与骑士团的首领做爱
Having sex with the Master of the Order.
我马上回来，你随意
Make yourself comfortable, I'll be right back.
举起手来，小白脸！
Hands in the air, lover boy! Lift them up!
督察，你不能逮捕我
Inspector, you cannot arrest me.
我是外国公民
I'm a foreign citizen,
我拥有奥地利共和国的外交豁免权
I have diplomatic immunity of the Republic of Austria.
我他妈才不在乎你的豁免权
I don't give a flying fuck about your immunity.
塔宁，看来你这次成功了
Tane, looks like you made it this time.
尽管黑公鸡目光呆滞
Despite the dull gaze of a blackcock.
还有笨拙的我
And my clumsiness.
如果我们第一次见面时有人告诉我
Had someone told me when we first met,
我们会成为搭档，我会让他们滚蛋
that we would become partners, I'd have given them a fuck off.
但是…
But, hey...
今天就到此为止吧，如果一切顺利的话
Let's not call it a day, but if all goes well,
肯定不是我的功劳
it won't be thanks to me, that's for sure.
是我们一起做的，我们的功劳
We did together. You and I.
你以为你是谁? 你以为这个镇是你的吗？
Who do you think you are? You think you own this town?
你以为你可以随心所欲地逮捕人！
You think you can arrest people as you wish!
- 我有确凿的证据 - 去你妈的证据
I have solid evidence. Fuck you and your evidence.
你把事情搞砸了，我们正要开会
You screwed up big time! We're about to have a conversation,
别担心，这可不是什么好事
and don't worry, it won't be a pleasant one.
把手铐解开，你在看什么，快点！
Take the cuffs off. What are you looking at, do it!
米里奇先生，对于这个误会我很抱歉
Mr. Mirich, I am very sorry about this misunderstanding
还有这里的人对待你的方式
and the way some here have treated you.
这种事时有发生
It happens.
走吧
Here you go.
你会后悔的
You'll regret this.
亲爱的督察们
My dear inspectors,
尽情享受阳光吧，直到夜幕降临…
enjoy it while you can, until the night falls...
议会大厦内有人开枪! 议会大厦内有人开枪！
Shots fired inside parliament! Shots fired inside parliament!
普尼沙 · 拉奇奇枪杀了克罗埃西亚农民党的国会议员
Punisha Rachich shot the MPs of Croatian Peasant Party.
克罗埃西亚农民党的领袖
Leader of the Croatian Peasant Party
为他的生命而战! 国会大厦内发生枪击案！
fighting for his life! Shots fired inside parliament!
国王考虑解散议会
The King considers dissolving the parliament.
督察，我们刚从国会回来！
Inspector, we just came from the parliament!
首相宣布进入紧急状态！
The minister called for the state of emergency!
- 大事不妙了! - 很久以前就不妙了
- The shit has hit the fan! - It had hit it a long time ago.
来吧，我们进去吧
C'mon, let's get inside.
马其顿 布科沃
THE VILLAGE OF BUKOVO, MACEDONIA
南斯拉夫王国
KINGDOM OF SERBS, CROATS, AND SLOVENES
给你，你叫什么名字？
Here you go. What's your name?
基拉! 基拉 · 格里戈洛夫
Kiro! Kiro Gligorov.
维也纳一致认为矛是赝品
The prevailing opinion in Vienna is that the spear is not authentic.
有人说俄国人的才是赝品
Some say that the Russians had the fake spear,
并且谎称这是真的
and were falsely claiming it was authentic.
还有人说俄国人也被欺骗了
Others say that Russians were deceived too.
最后有人说俄国人拿到的是真品
Finally, some say that the Russians had the real one,
仍然在这里，在贝尔格莱德
and that it is still here, in Belgrade.
我希望维也纳的人们足够聪明
I hope that people in Vienna are wise enough
不要把这场争论变成一场公开辩论
not to turn this argument into a public debate.
他们永远不会
They would never.
所以，真正的矛在维也纳
So, the authentic spear is in Vienna.
没错
That's right.
先生们，请注意
Gentlemen, may I have your attention, please.
特权出口公司"Prizad"
The privileged export company "Prizad",
将成为我国农民和外国买家之间的桥梁
will represent a bridge between our farmers and foreign buyers.
这将是我们王国改革开放
It will be a major step
重要的一步
for our kingdom's bid to open up to the world.
政府特此任命一位杰出的企业家
The government hereby appoints a prominent entrepreneur,
赞助人和伟大的慈善家
patron and a great philanthropist,
作为公司的经理，阿里姆皮耶 · 米里奇先生
as the company's manager. Mr. Alimpiye Mirich
下午好
Good afternoon.
- 下午好 - 致以我最深的敬意
- Good afternoon. - My deepest respect.
基拉先生，我真的很抱歉
Mr. Kyro, I am truly sorry.
- 请坐 - 谢谢
- Have a seat. - Thank you.
阿尔索夫先生，我向您表示最深切的哀悼
Mr. Hadzhi-Arsov, my deepest condolences...
你大老远跑来不只是为了表示哀悼吧？
You didn't travel this far just to offer your condolences.
是，也不是
Yes... Yes and no.
- 请坐 - 谢谢
- Sit. - Thanks.
你有一分钟时间，长话短说
You have one minute, so be brief.
- 日沃音！- 是，长官
- Zhivoyin! - Yes, chief.
你把这个给那两个人，但不是现在
You'll give this to those two, but not now.
等他们冷静下来
When they cool off.
普莱蒂科西奇会回瑞士深造
Pletikosich is going back to study in Switzerland,
塔纳西耶维奇会去度假休息，恢复体力
and Tanasiyevich is going to a spa for some rest and recuperation.
如果他拒绝，他可以去地狱
If he refuses, he can go to hell.
带他们去喝几杯
Take them out, treat them to a couple of drinks.
照顾我的宪兵
And look after my gendarmes.
老斯拉夫人过去常说
Old Slavs used to say:
“穿过荆棘才能触碰到星辰”
"Through the thorns to the stars".
不幸的是，在我们这里，荆棘更茂盛
Unfortunately, in this part of the world, thorns are bigger,
而且比其他地方更锋利
and sharper, than in many other places.
但是又能怎么办呢？
But what can you do?
还有什么，是比触碰星辰
What else are we to do,
更重要的事情？
than to reach out for the stars.
你会合作吗？
Will you cooperate?
走着瞧
We'll see. We'll see.
我想提议
I wanted to propose a partnership
为了达到共同的目标而合作
in obtaining a common goal.
那是什么目标呢？
And what goal would that be?
刺杀亚历山大 · 卡拉德约尔 · 杰维奇国王
Assassinating King Alexander Karadjordjevich.
你不会打电话给我，督察
You're not calling me, inspector.
你不想? 还是你和你前妻复合了？
You don't want to? Or you're back with your ex?
我不会回到任何人身边
I'm not going back to anyone.
我在强制休假，一个人
I'm on a compulsory vacation. Alone.
是的，你喜欢独处
Yes, you like solitude.
你对你的同事要离开感到遗憾吗？
Are you sorry your colleague is leaving?
是的，他是个好人，我会想念他的
I am. He's a good guy. I'll miss him.
那我呢..
And what about me...
你会想我吗？
Will you miss me?
我会的
I will.
你知道，我们不合适
You know I'm not for you.
我不知道，但看起来你知道
I don't. But it seems like you do.
我知道
I do.
我们才刚刚开始这个游戏，你就放弃了
You're giving up, and we've only just started this game.
你在玩一个危险的游戏
It's a dangerous game you're playing.
- 你还是不信任我 - 我信任你
- You still don't trust me. - I trust you.
信任你的人不多，但我是信任你的
I am one of the few, but I trust you.
我会一直在你身边
And I'll always be there for you.
- 不管你需要什么 - 不，我不会给你打电话的
- Whatever you need. - No, I won't be calling you.
如果你需要什么就给我打电话
You call me if you need something.
你不欠我什么，而我欠你一条命
You don't owe me anything, I owe you my life.
虽然... 你很清楚..
Although... It is obviously clear to you...
我欠你的一文不值
that what I owe you is not worth much.
无法用言语表达我们的感激之情
There are no words to express our gratitude
他们送了最好的礼物给我们
to those wonderful people. They gave us the best gift ever.
那孩子是上帝赐予的礼物
That child is a gift from God.
非常感谢你，你给我们的生活带来了欢乐
Thank you very much, you brought joy into our lives.
不用客气
You're welcome.
现在米莉亚要开那瓶为我们儿子出生准备的
Now Milya is going to open that twenty-year-old brandy
陈年的白兰地了
that I was saving for the birth of my son.
- 二十年？- 二十年
- Twenty years? - Twenty.
我们真的得走了
We really have to go now.
好吧，斯坦科，祝你旅途愉快
Well, Stanko, have a nice trip, and I hope you'll be celebrating
希望你的孩子在瑞士出生
the birth of your child in Switzerland.
- 至少三个孩子，博雅娜 - 谢谢
- At least three, Boyana. - Thank you.
- 谢谢 - 谢谢
- Thank you. - Thank you.
教授，这是我的荣幸
Professor, it was my honour.
你的儿媳妇会给你生孙子的，别担心
Your daughter-in-law is going to give you grandchildren, don't worry.
他将要给她孩子
He is going to make her babies,
而你，巴比奇，你会和尸体一起腐烂
and you, Babich, rot with the corpses.
教授，我现在可以吻你了吗？
Professor, may I kiss you now?
当然，能和你一起工作是我的荣幸
Of course. It was a pleasure and honour to work with you.
好吧，督察，保重
Well, inspector, take care.
- 你好好照顾他 - 我会的
- You take good care of him. - I will.
在他遇见你之前，他是个好孩子
Before he met you, inspector, he was a good boy,
现在他是个好人
and now he's a good man.
- 来吧，爷爷，我们走 - 我们走
- C'mon, grandpa, let's go. - Let's go.
我们在等你
We're waiting for you.
看，你把他变成了一个男人，然后他就离开了你
See, you make a man out of them, and then they leave you.
别担心，那个男人会回来的
Don't worry, the man will come back.
说实话，我不认为你应该回来
To tell you the truth, I'm not sure you should.
你不需要回到这个粪坑
You don't need this shit.
你呢？
How about you?
我不知道，但不用担心我
I have no idea, but don't worry about me.
那么，你真的爱她，你真的信任她？
So, you do love her and you do trust her?
我甚至不再相信自己
I don't even trust myself anymore.
保重
Take care.
别在瑞士学坏了
Don't turn dim in that Switzerland again.
我尽量
I'll try.
敞篷车里的这位年轻女士？
A convertible for the young lady, huh?
她对你来说是不是有点老了？
Isn't she a bit old for you?
你们这些混蛋! 干杯！
You fuckers! Cheers!
干杯！
Cheers!
迪玛 · 塔纳西耶维奇
Dima Tanasiyevich
米哈伊洛! 叶利萨维塔！
Mihailo! Yelisavetha!
有何吩咐，陛下？
Yes, Your Majesty?
把这垃圾拿出去！
Take this trash out!
扔掉它! 黑色太阳的作品已经结束了
Throw it away! The Black Sun opus is over.
贝尔格莱德警察局
BELGRADE POLICE DEPARTMENT
请到火车站去
To the railway station, please.
让我们欢迎新的领袖
Let's hail the new leader.
敬礼！
Salute!
你有什么新点子吗？
You have something new in mind?
我不确定，但不管是什么
I am not sure, but whatever it is,
可能依然…
it'll probably be...
是黑色的
black again.
第一季结束
END OF SEASON ONE